<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Fermi Problem - series - Jim W. Kennington</title><link>http://locallytrivial.com/series/fermi-problem/</link><description>Fermi Problem - series - Jim W. Kennington</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://locallytrivial.com/series/fermi-problem/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fermi Friday: Galactic Spaghetti</title><link>http://locallytrivial.com/posts/fermi-friday-20211008/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Jim Kennington</author><guid>http://locallytrivial.com/posts/fermi-friday-20211008/</guid><description>Often in discussions about blackholes, the question arises of observer experience when falling into a blackhole. Due to the extreme tidal forces experienced along such a path, the observer would be stretched out - a process colloquially referred to as spaghettification. This week I would like to look at a happier use for spaghetti near blackholes. If an observer in a stable circular orbit around the supermassive blackhole at the center of our galaxy were to use spaghetti as a tether, how much spaghetti would be required?</description></item><item><title>Fermi Friday: Baseball Blackhole</title><link>http://locallytrivial.com/posts/fermi-friday-20210924/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Jim Kennington</author><guid>http://locallytrivial.com/posts/fermi-friday-20210924/</guid><description>The question of interest this week is:
If all baseballs ever used in an MLB game were compressed into a blackhole, how large would the blackhole be?
To estimate the blackhole radius $r_{BH}$, we&amp;rsquo;ll need to compute the number of baseballs used in MLB games, translate that number to a total mass, then compute the blackhole radius of the corresponding mass.
Counting Baseballs We begin with a lower-bound on the number of baseballs used in all MLB games.</description></item><item><title>Fermi Friday: A Different Manhattan Project</title><link>http://locallytrivial.com/posts/fermi-friday-20210917/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Jim Kennington</author><guid>http://locallytrivial.com/posts/fermi-friday-20210917/</guid><description>For this week&amp;rsquo;s installment of Fermi estimation, the question of interest is:
How fast would the sun burn an amount of hydrogen equivalent to the above-ground mass of Manhattan?
To estimate the burn-time we&amp;rsquo;ll need to guess at a few quantities: the above-ground mass of Manhattan, the solar luminosity (total energy emitted from the sun), and fraction of energy emitted from the core of the sun that makes it to the surface.</description></item></channel></rss>