<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Blog Stack - Tag - Jim W. Kennington</title><link>http://locallytrivial.com/tags/blog-stack/</link><description>Blog Stack - Tag - Jim W. Kennington</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>jameswkennington@psu.edu (Jim Kennington)</managingEditor><webMaster>jameswkennington@psu.edu (Jim Kennington)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://locallytrivial.com/tags/blog-stack/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Migration to Hugo</title><link>http://locallytrivial.com/posts/migration-to-hugo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jameswkennington@psu.edu (Jim Kennington)</author><guid>http://locallytrivial.com/posts/migration-to-hugo/</guid><description>Motivation With the ebb of workload from first year graduate courses, I decided to rekindle the blog that I had setup a couple years prior. As a former professional Python developer, I had chosen Pelican as my static site generator (SSG) in late 2018. The set of plugins looked sufficient, and I could always write my own if needed. Fast-forward to this week, and the situation is different. The Hugo community has grown, broadened, and supported more use cases.</description></item><item><title>Standup, Hugo! Creating a Blog with Hugo</title><link>http://locallytrivial.com/posts/standup-hugo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jameswkennington@psu.edu (Jim Kennington)</author><guid>http://locallytrivial.com/posts/standup-hugo/</guid><description><![CDATA[Preliminaries Let&rsquo;s quickly review what you&rsquo;ll need to build a Hugo blog, and what it will mean to have a Hugo blog at the end of the process.
What You&rsquo;ll Need Before we begin, you&rsquo;ll need a few things. I&rsquo;ll list the essentials below (as well as my recommendations where relevant)
Git, the ubiquitous VCS of the era GitHub account, for storing your blog content (and hosting for free!) Text Editor, for writing content and editing configuration files (I recommend either Sublime Text for simple uses or GoLand for those who also need to edit GO code for plugins) What You&rsquo;ll Have By the end of this post, the hope is that you will have:]]></description></item></channel></rss>